[
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Pradhan Mantri Anusuchit Jaati Abhyuday Yojana (PM- AJAY) Scheme:  1. It is aimed at reducing poverty among the Scheduled Castes communities through various initiatives.  2. It is a 100% Centrally Sponsored Scheme.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct? \u27a2 North Korea announced testing of an anti-aircraft Pyoljji-1-2 missile and a super large strategic cruise missile Hwasal-1 Ra-3 warhead in the West Sea of Korea \u27a2 India has conducted the first successful flight test of nuclear ballistic missile Agni-5. Agni-5 missile developed under Make in India project by DRDO. \u27a2 Agni 5 missile is the longest range missile of the Agni series with a range of over 5000 km.  Follow us: Official Site, Telegram, Facebook, Instagram, Youtube 122",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "India has set a target to eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis by which year?",
        "options": [
            "2027 ",
            "2028 ",
            "2030 ",
            "2029 "
        ],
        "answer": "2027 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country hosted the third international conference on artificial intelligence \u201cAI Action Summit\u201d in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Australia  ",
            "Germany  ",
            "France  ",
            "Italy "
        ],
        "answer": "France  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country was \"Operation Devil Hunt\" launched to crack down on violence?",
        "options": [
            "Myanmar ",
            "Bangladesh ",
            "Sri Lanka ",
            "Nepal "
        ],
        "answer": "Bangladesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is set to host the world's largest Jhumur festival in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "West Bengal ",
            "Assam ",
            "Odisha ",
            "Jharkhand "
        ],
        "answer": "Assam ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Indian Army conducts a joint military Exercise Cyclone with which country's Armed Forces?",
        "options": [
            "Egypt  ",
            "Indonesia  ",
            "Malaysia  ",
            "Australia  "
        ],
        "answer": "Egypt  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who launched India\u2019s first indigenous automated biomedical waste treatment plant \"Srijanam\"?",
        "options": [
            "Narendra Modi ",
            "Dr. Jitendra Singh ",
            "Mansukh Mandaviya ",
            "Amit Shah "
        ],
        "answer": "Dr. Jitendra Singh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will the Olympic Esports Games 2027 be held?",
        "options": [
            "Tokyo ",
            "Ottawa ",
            "Riyadh ",
            "Berlin "
        ],
        "answer": "Riyadh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization has recently released the report titled \u201cLeveraging Space Technology for Agricultural Development and Food Security\u201d?",
        "options": [
            "Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) ",
            "United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP) ",
            "World Bank ",
            "International Monetary Fund (IMF) "
        ],
        "answer": "Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Department for Promotion of Industry and Internal Trade (DPIIT) has signed an agreement with which organization for logistics and infrastructure development?",
        "options": [
            "World Bank ",
            "IMF ",
            "Korea Transport Institute ",
            "IIT Delhi "
        ],
        "answer": "Korea Transport Institute ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the 2025 Chennai Open Tennis men\u2019s single title?",
        "options": [
            "Kyrian Jacquet ",
            "Elias Ymer ",
            "Dalibor Svrcina ",
            "Billy Harris "
        ],
        "answer": "Kyrian Jacquet ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cook Islands, that was recently seen in news, is located in which ocean?",
        "options": [
            "South Pacific Ocean ",
            "Atlantic Ocean ",
            "Indian Ocean ",
            "Arctic Ocean "
        ],
        "answer": "South Pacific Ocean ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which wildlife sanctuary has been selected as India\u2019s second cheetah habitat?",
        "options": [
            "Hazaribagh Wildlife Sanctuary ",
            "Gandhi Sagar Wildlife Sanctuary ",
            "Kamlang Wildlife Sanctuary ",
            "Chandoli Wildlife Sanctuary "
        ],
        "answer": "Gandhi Sagar Wildlife Sanctuary ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which institution has launched a policy report titled Expanding Quality Higher Education through States and State Public Universities?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Education ",
            "Reserve Bank of India ",
            "NITI Aayog ",
            "IIT Kanpur "
        ],
        "answer": "NITI Aayog ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where has India\u2019s largest solar cell and module manufacturing unit been inaugurated?",
        "options": [
            "Gujarat ",
            "Tamil Nadu ",
            "Karnataka ",
            "Madhya Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Tamil Nadu ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the rank of India in the 2024 Corruption Perception Index?",
        "options": [
            "75th ",
            "96th ",
            "86th ",
            "46th "
        ],
        "answer": "96th ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was ranked the most corrupt in the 2024 Corruption Perception Index?",
        "options": [
            "South Sudan ",
            "Somalia ",
            "Venezuela ",
            "Kuwait "
        ],
        "answer": "South Sudan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is not among the top five in the Corruption Perceptions Index (CPI) 2025 released by Transparency International?",
        "options": [
            "Denmark  ",
            "Finland  ",
            "Singapore ",
            "Norway "
        ],
        "answer": "Norway ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Corruption Perception Index (CPI) is released annually by:",
        "options": [
            "World Economic Forum ",
            "Transparency International ",
            "Reporters without Borders ",
            "United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) "
        ],
        "answer": "Transparency International ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding Market Intervention Scheme:  1. It is a component of the integrated scheme of PM-AASHA.  2. It is implemented to all farm produces whose price reduces to 10% in the prevailing market price as compared to the previous normal year.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of rice has India introduced new HS codes for to facilitate exports?",
        "options": [
            "GI-Tagged Rice ",
            "Basmati Rice ",
            "Hybrid Rice ",
            "Non-Basmati Rice  "
        ],
        "answer": "GI-Tagged Rice ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian company has acquired a 49% stake in Oval Invincibles, a franchise in the England and Wales Cricket Board\u2019s (ECB) The Hundred?",
        "options": [
            "The Hundred? ",
            "Wipro Group  ",
            "Tata Group ",
            "Reliance Industries ",
            "Adani Group "
        ],
        "answer": "Tata Group ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the sports drink recently launched by Reliance Consumer Products?",
        "options": [
            "Hydrate Plus ",
            "Spinner ",
            "SportyFizz ",
            "Fresh Boost "
        ],
        "answer": "Spinner ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state will host the 39th edition of the National Games in 2027?",
        "options": [
            "Assam ",
            "Meghalaya ",
            "Manipur ",
            "Sikkim "
        ],
        "answer": "Meghalaya ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Fishery Survey of India (FSI):  1. It is the nodal fishery institute in India under the Ministry of Fisheries, Animal Husbandry, and Dairying.  2. The primary responsibility of FSI is the survey and assessment of fishery resources in the Indian exclusive economic zone (EEZ) and adjoining areas.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Panchayat Devolution Index:  1. It evaluates framework, capacity building and accountability of the Panchayats.  2. It provides transparency in tracking Panchayat functioning and resource allocation to citizens.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Asian Fisheries and Aquaculture Forum:  1. It is a triennial event of the Asian Fisheries Society which has a strong legacy of fostering global collaboration in the sector.  2. Its headquarter is located in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new CEO of Nokia, effective April 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Sari Baldauf ",
            "Pekka Lundmark ",
            "Justin Hotard ",
            "Pat Gelsinger "
        ],
        "answer": "Justin Hotard ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country signed an Executive Programme of Cooperation (EPC) with India for archival cooperation from 2025 to 2028?",
        "options": [
            "with India for archival ",
            "Oman ",
            "UAE ",
            "Saudi Arabia ",
            "Qatar "
        ],
        "answer": "with India for archival ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the 2025 Annual Conference of the International Institute of Administrative Science (IIAS) held?",
        "options": [
            "New Delhi  ",
            "Hyderabad  ",
            "Bengaluru  ",
            "Chennai "
        ],
        "answer": "New Delhi  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the 12th edition of the World Government Summit 2025 held?",
        "options": [
            "Dubai  ",
            "London  ",
            "Paris  ",
            "New York "
        ],
        "answer": "Dubai  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Bank has launched India's first salary account with cyber fraud protection for PSU employees?",
        "options": [
            "HDFC Bank  ",
            "Yes Bank  ",
            "ICICI Bank  ",
            "Axis Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "HDFC Bank  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following has expanded the scope of the Unified Payments Interface (UPI) by allowing Small Finance Banks (SFBs) to offer pre-sanctioned credit lines for UPI transactions?",
        "options": [
            "NPCI ",
            "RBI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "IRDAI "
        ],
        "answer": "RBI ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has lifted supervisory restrictions imposed on which bank?",
        "options": [
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank ",
            "Indian Overseas Bank  ",
            "Canara Bank  ",
            "Indian Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Kotak Mahindra Bank ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The latest issued banknotes in the denomination of Rs. 50 by RBI have what motif on their reverse side?",
        "options": [
            "Red Fort ",
            "Sanchi Stupa ",
            "Mangalyaan ",
            "Stone chariot of Hampi "
        ],
        "answer": "Stone chariot of Hampi ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the MITRA Platform:  1. It assists investors in tracking and reclaiming inactive or unclaimed mutual fund folios.  2. It is an initiative of the Reserve Bank of India.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity has tied up with AFD, under which the French lender will provide a $100 million credit line?",
        "options": [
            "RBI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "SIDBI ",
            "NPCI "
        ],
        "answer": "SIDBI ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]